Mama?
It's always your dad who comes to fetch you.
Daikichi isn't my dad.
Grandpa is my dad.
What?
That's just weird!
Anyone will have a mom and dad.
Then what is Daikichi to you?
I don't know.
Rin-chan is always saying some strange stuff.
Guys can't give birth to kids, you know.
Shut up!
It's okay not to have a dad. Idiots!
The one who says that to others is the stupid one.
Idiots! Idiots! Idiots!
Hiro-Sensei!
Let's go.
Kouki-kun said I'm an idiot!
Hiro-Sensei!
At Kouki-kun's place, there's only your mom?
Dad went off somewhere we don't know, so they divorced.
What's a divorce?
Means they're no longer married.
Is my mom also not here because of divorce?
No idea.
You'll get yelled at if you don't wear your hat.
What?
Your string is loose.
Rin-chan, he's here for you!
Rin-chan!
Daikichi's here!
Rin-tan, chomeone's...
Ma-kun, it's all right.
Thank you very much.
See you next time, Rin-chan.
Goodbye!
What do you want for dinner?
Let's see.
Kouki-Kun!
Your mom is here for you!
Oyatsu Fansubs Presents
Usagi
Drop
ashita no koto ha wakannai
明日のことは　分かんない
We don't know what's going to happen tomorrow.
korette gisei toha chigau nanika ga chigau
これって　犠牲とは違う　何かが違う
This is different from sacrificing, very different.
batsugeemu jaa nante omou wa nai
罰ゲームじゃあ　なんて思うわない
I don't think this is a punishment game either.
tte nande nanoka ha wakannai
って　なんでなのかは　分かんない
I can't really say well what it is.
chotto shakuzen to shinai kedo
ちょっと　釈然としないけど
In fact, I do feel quite troubled,
kimi no sonzai ima daiji da nantemonjanai
キミの存在　今大事だ　なんてもんじゃない
but "important" cannot be used to describe your existence any more.
owaranai koto nante konoyo no dokonimonai
終わらないことなんて　この世のどこにもない
There's nothing that will last forever without coming to an end.
naku no ha tsurai janai no
泣くのは辛いじゃないの
Crying is a very painful thing
I know! Sweet drops! Sweet drops!
zutto yume mite itaine
ずっと　夢見ていたいね
I have always wanted to dream
motto yasashiku shitaine
もっと　優しくしたいね
To be able to be more gentle
kimi to iraretara happy!
キミと居られたら　happy!
Just being together with you is happy.
onnanoko tte tsuyoi ne
女の子って　強いね
Girls are strong,
dakedo tokidoki yowai ne
だけど　時々　弱いね
but at times, they are weak.
bokura no negai ha happy! happy! happy...
僕らの願いは　happy! happy! happy...
Our wish is to be happy! Happy! Happy!
sonna hibi mo happy!
そんな日々も happy!
Such happy days!
Just wanna make you happy...
Your mom is really beautiful.
But she's an irritating old hag at home.
Kouki seems to be always under her care.
R-Really?
My son is hard to get along with, so he wasn't able to make any friends.
I'm really thankful for that.
No no, it's nothing. W-We should thank you instead.
Rin's also very hard to get along with.
I guess they get along because they're so alike.
Daikichi, you were talking about me just now, right?
I didn't say anything bad.
Now quick, go ahead.
Don't ask me to carry you on the way later.
I won't!
Let's go.
She seems to be more attached to you, her father.
Oh, I'm not her father.
Well, something like her relative?
I'm sorry, seriously me.
No, it's fine.
Mom, you're so slow!
Isn't it great that you made a friend?
Yep!
You know Kouki-kun? He doesn't have a dad.
What?
He said they're divorced and they're not sure where he is.
By divorce, do you know what it means?
Yeah. It means they're no longer married, right?
Well, something like that.
He'll probably be punished if God knows about this.
Is my mom also not here because of divorce?
Do you want to see her?
I don't know.
I see.
But, you know?
What?
I want to see her if she's as pretty as Kouki-Kun's mom.
Me too! Me too!
What did you say?
Rin-chan's mother?
Yeah, the assistant at Grandpa's house is probably Rin's mother.
No way.
About that assistant, do you know anything about her?
This doesn't look too bad.
A farewell party for me?
Sorry for having it so late.
I've finally finished planning for the Winter costumes.
Thanks for the offer, but I can't go out at night.
She's only six, that kid at my house.
Don't tell me you haven't gone drinking even once since then?
Yeah, I can't go means I can't.
Besides, going out drinking no longer means that much to me.
I guess I'm getting old.
About that, you're only in your thirties.
Speaking of which, our people here may be young, but most of them have kids.
They don't even have the drinking habit, right?
Yeah, not at all.
I have to go to the daycare to fetch the kids.
The youngest of the two at my place is only three months old.
If I don't hurry back, my wife will...
Yeah, what a monster wife.
It's pretty frightening if she gets mad.
Kawachi-kun~
Gotou-san.
I've heard about the farewell party.
Yeah. But it's impossible, since it's at night.
It's not something you get everyday; just bring along your kid.
I'm bringing my kid along too.
You're actually thinking of going out drinking once in a while-
Well, there's nothing bad about that.
Hey, I'm waiting for your good news.
Coming!
Daikichi, the phone.
Thank you.
Hello.
Is this Daikichi?
Your Grandpa seems to have gotten the assistant from the agency.
Wait a minute.
Do you have her name?
Yoshii Masako-san, comes from "righteous", while ko is from "children".
Yoshii Masako 吉井正子, 正(Masa/Tadashii 正しい)=correct/righteous, 子(ko) from 子供(kodomo)=child.
Hey, that's the name that's written on the MCH Handbook, right?
Seems like it.
Don't tell me you intend to contact her?
Any person who could abandon such an adorable girl-
Calm down a bit, will you?
You've seen the MCH Handbook, right?
There are so many things written there.
There are still so many things we aren't sure of yet.
Excuse me!
That's why I said, work and family!
Sorry for being late.
You're late! Sit over here!
Stay away, you drunkard!
Rin-chan?
You came after all.
Thanks a lot!
Ah, she's so cute~!
Eat as much as you like.
Here you go.
Thank you for gracing us, Rin-chan.
Thanks.
Here, Rin-chan.
Do you like orange juice?
Yes.
Rin-chan is such a beauty.
Yes, a fine beauty.
She's blushing.
So cute~
Yuu-kun, I'll help you gather them together.
Thanks a lot, Rin-chan.
Kawachi-san, drink more.
Rin might fall asleep on the way back.
I'm going to the restroom, Rin.
Note: Daikichi uses 便所 (benjo) instead of トイレ (toire), which both mean the same thing.
Use "toilet"!
Yeah right, toilet toilet.
He abandoned everybody in the section.
He shouldn't leave such an impressive record when he's about to leave.
Running away after winning, how despicable.
The sales outlook for this month won't be optimistic.
Even if the sales are decent, it definitely won't compare to last year's.
What to do?
I can't do it anymore.
The me in the past would have jumped in, angry.
Oh dear, it's coming out.
Girls are so soft!
Now I feel like bringing you home.
The most important things to me have already changed.
Kawachi-san.
What?
About your transfer.
I understand somehow, after seeing Rin-chan.
Right?
I feel like just carrying you like this.
Mama, Mama, carry me.
Gotou-san, she doesn't like it.
Hey, Mama.
Masako-san, how do you feel about children?
How do you feel about Rin?
Yuu-kun is so cute.
You really like small kids.
Yeah, there's a letter.
Oh, thank you.
There's going to be an elementary school entrance explanation meeting.
I did nothing, and yet such a letter has been sent.
What's wrong?
Will there be an entrance test?
No, not at all!
You don't have to take the test to enrol.
Really?
Absolutely.
Compulsory education is impressive!
Drunkard~
Oh, darn, how's that?
Rin-chan, he's here.
S-Sorry.
Sheesh, everyone already left.
Sorry.
Kouki-kun! Your mom is here!
I'm sorry, Kouki.
H-Hello.
It's been... a while.
Can we still make it, Daikichi?
I'll go and flag down a cab.
Excuse me.
Osu Elementary School
The name tags we use here can be rotated.
Please remember to flip it over, so as not to reveal the child's name while commuting.
Also, don't leave your child alone in areas such as the park.
Remind your child not to go off with anyone even if they know them.
It's sad, isn't it?
The first things we teach our children is to doubt people, rather than trust them.
Yeah.
The form that I took just now...
I'll help you.
How do I know what kind of immunizations she's gotten?
What?
S-Sorry about that.
I seem to have asked a senseless question.
It's fine. Do you have Rin-chan's MCH Handbook?
Yes, it's at home.
There's a particular page that has them recorded.
So don't worry about it.
I-I see.
I really don't know anything.
I only met Rin for the first time three months ago.
What? Three months ago?
Yeah...
That's hard to believe.  It looks like Rin-chan really trusts you.
Is that so?
She always talks back to me at home, and also talks non-stop.
That proves that she trusts you.
No matter how I look at it, both of you look like a family.
Family...
R-Really?
Yes.
I guess it's true then.
What?
I jumped across your shadow.
I'm not tired.
It doesn't matter.
Put me down! Put me down!
I said, put me down!
Oh, thank you.
It's almost ready.
Backpack?
I haven't bought it.
That won't do!
The branded and nice looking ones are going to be sold out.
I don't see the fuss. I can just buy the normal ones.
Because she's a girl, so it won't do.
Well, I'll take a look on the weekend.
Dai-chan, do you intend to continue raising Rin-chan like that?
I mean, you even transferred to a different section, didn't you?
I haven't given much thought about the future.
Mama!
Now, Reina will help you dry off.
All right.
You two get along very well.
Yeah.
Mothers and daughters get along just like friends.
Now that I think about it, Mom and Kazumi get along very well, too.
Maybe Masako-san's situation has changed, and she wants to live together with her child.
That is possible.
She's gotten so many shots.
This is indeed being a mother- What?
Souichi's Will
Dapyon!
A will? ...Dapyon?
"This'll most likely get deleted if Masako-san notices it."
"So I chose this sort of under window approach."
"But I don't know the proper way of writing a secret book."
"Besides, I'm trifling this strange keyboard thing having no progress at all."
This is impressive, even if it's supposed to be wrong usage of words.
"It seems like this old man's is out of energy, thus I decide to give up the blog."
You give up way too fast!
You're born in the Taishou era!
"The rest to be continued in Rin-chan's MCH Handbook."
Sorry Rin, I'm taking a look.
"I believe the person who finds this letter is someone who treats Rin like family."
"This will explain certain things about Rin and her mother, Masako."
"Masako is a person who is easily misunderstood."
"I'm saying clearly that she isn't a bad person."
"She said she isn't fit to be a mother."
"She feels bad for Rin."
"So she's only willing to appear before Rin as a house assistant."
"I believe she will continue to do so even now."
"She feels that this will bring Rin most happiness."
Happiness?
What's going on?
"Even if something happens to me,"
"she will be able to hide her identity in front of our relatives..."
"...in order to carry on living cautiously without a trace."
"Masako really does love Rin as a mother."
"But she's still very young."
"Perhaps she isn't mature enough to be a mother."
I don't really get what he's trying to say.
But I can tell he holds important feelings for Rin and her mother.
There's no question about that.
Yoshii Masako
Daikichi!
W-What do you want?
You see, I want you to tie my hair up like a bunny.
What?
Just like what Reina-chan's mom did for me.
No way!
Do it.
Absolutely not! It's impossible.
Tie it for me!
Because... I am not cute.
Who said that?
Mi-chan said "Rin-chan is not cute at all."
What?
No matter how I see it, Rin wins hands down.
I want to look cute too.
Okay.
She's already becoming a full fledged girl.
For her to care about things like this.
Masako-san, do you know?
Rin's inner feelings have matured considerably.
No, some areas are maturing while others are not.
That's why we adults should look after her properly, isn't it?
Ouch.
All done.
This is!
Twinkle twinkle little star~ How I wonder-
Hey Rin, what are you doing?
The Games Meet is supposed to be kept a secret from the family.
What? A Games Meet?
So you shouldn't look!
S-So you're participating in that hairstyle?
Twinkle twinkle little star~
How I wonder what you are~
Yoshii Masako
If the reason you abandoned Rin is to forget about painful memories of the past,
I won't hesitate to hate you.
I hope you have some sort of unique circumstance.
Twinkle twinkle little star~
But...
How I wonder what you are~
...something that could even lead to abandoning a child.
Just what is it?
Study Desk
Study Chair
This one looks cute!
It's true that it's cute.
But you're going to be using it for a long time.
We need something more...
That's right!
How about something more big-sister-ish?
Big sister?
All right, I want something more big-sister-ish!
Yes!
You're sitting again?
Do I look like a big sister?
Yeah, this desk set will still be okay even until you become a high school student.
Is a high school student an adult?
I guess it's about halfway there.
Listen to my reading.
A girl went into the forest alone to play.
The girl lost her way, and she tried really hard to find her way back.
But she couldn't find it, no matter how hard she tried.
She suddenly realised there was a tiny cottage in the forest.
Is this Yoshii-san speaking?
What? Yeah, that's me.
nichiyou no hare ta hirusagari
日曜の晴れた昼下がり
On a clear Sunday afternoon
kyou ha doko he yukou
今日はどこへ行こう
Where are we heading today?
kayoi nareta itsumono michi ga mabushiku kagayaite mieru
通いなれたいつもの道が　まぶしく輝いて見える
The usual road that we always take seems to be shining radiantly
terasu atatakai taiyou to tonari ni kimi ga ireba
照らすあたたかい太陽と　となりに君がいれば
The warm sun is shining with you still by my side
mou High High High
もう　High　High　High
We're already high, high, high!
hashagidasu kimochi ni
はしゃぎだす気持ちに
While we're feeling so merry
utae rairairai
歌えライライライ
Sing Rai, Rai, Rai!
koe ha doko made mo
声はどこまでも
Our voices are everywhere
mou High High High
もう　High　High　High
We're already high, high, high!
maiagaru kaze ni nori
まいあがる風にのり
Riding on the soaring wind
utae rairairai
歌えライライライ
Sing Rai, Rai, Rai!
koe mo tobi haneru
声も飛び跳ねる
Our voices are hopping too
This is pretty cute.
Oh, not again!
Rin!?
Rin!
Hey!
Daikichi?
I thought I told you not to run off on your own!
Yes~
What's that?
Something that will turn me into a big sister.
No way!
This will have to wait for a few years.
Why?